Stanislav Pogorskii – React / Next.js Frontend Developer

Georgia (ready to relocate) | +995511107834 | <u>stanislav.pogorskii@gmail.com</u>
https://www.linkedin.com/in/pogorskii/ | https://t.me/staspogorsky

SUMMARY

Diligent and highly versatile developer with more than 2 years of experience working with HTML, CSS (+SASS, Tailwind), JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript, React and Next.js. Always learning new technologies and improving existing skills.

Passionate for creating modern, accessible and effective websites and web applications. Prefers Next.js/TypeScript, but ready to use any language/framework best suited for a given task.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance

February 2022 - November 2023

Frontend Developer

Remote

- Built landing pages for small businesses with **vanilla HTML/CSS/JS**, implementing **pixel-perfect** recreations of given designs, and also making the sites completely responsive for every resolution, pixel density and device type.
- Created a fully custom order-price calculator for visitors of a cleaning company, using **JQuery**. It resulted in a **50% conversion rate increase** for the business and reduced the time of registering orders from 40-60 minutes to around **10-15 minutes**.
- Built a template for a car-service business and made it modular, which helped the owner reuse the same design for 6 of their other related services.
- Created a dynamic landing for a cybersport-related service using **React**, **Tailwind**, and **Bootstrap** much **faster** than the client expected me to.

Sports.ru June 2019 – Present

Head Editor of Games and Movies | January 2022 - Present

Remote

- Lead a team of **10** authors.
- Established connections with **30+** publishers and gaming companies.
- Created and implemented a content strategy that increased monthly traffic by 150%+.
- Ensured that my team consistently met deadlines.

Author | June 2019 – December 2021

■ Prior to my promotion to Head Editor, I worked as a versatile author. My responsibilities included writing engaging articles, reporting from events and taking interviews.

PROJECTS

WIITCO (When Is It Coming Out)

October 2022 - Present

Live: https://wiitco.vercel.app | Code: https://github.com/pogorskii/wiitco-app

- Created a modern NextJS/TypeScript SPA that solves a real-world problem.
- Combined vastly different APIs into a cohesive and comfortable UI.
- Set up PostgreSQL to store movies, tv shows and video games data.
- Converted external games DB from error-prone noSQL to robust PostgreSQL.
- Implemented additional Go backend to handle DB syncing.
- Implemented Auth0 authentication.

SKILLS

Frontend: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Next.js, Astro,

Tailwind, D3.js, jQuery.

Backend: TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, Go, AuthO, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Prisma, Gorm,

Zod.

Tools & Best Practices: Git, GitHub, Figma, a11y, DRY, BEM, Clean Code, SEO, Mobile-first,

UI/UX Assessment, Pixel-perfect, Responsive.

Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Teamwork, Adaptability, Communication, Stress Resilience,

Accountability, Time Management.

Languages: Russian (Native), English (C1), German (A1).

EDUCATION

Khimki College of Space Engineering

2017

Lower post-secondary vocational education in Programming

Moscow, Russia

■ Chose web development-related tasks for all of my graduation projects, including creating web apps with vanilla JavaScript and working with MySQL databases.

CERTIFICATIONS

The Complete JavaScript Course 2023: From Zero to Expert! JavaScript

2023

Udemy